(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-30T05:26:10.816093",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Takane Lui Lapis Lazuli 重大告知
[Takane Lui: Lapis Lazuli - Major Announcement]
NEXT CHAPTER LAPIS LAZULI
Takane Lui Lapis Lazuli 鷹嶺ルイ 重大告知 LIVE
[Takane Lui: Lapis Lazuli - Major Announcement LIVE]
宵の口十中八九で 面倒くささを突きつけられてる
Nine times out of ten in the early night, being confronted with annoying trouble,
何から何まで
from start to finish.
四苦八苦やめて また見栄張ったって
Stop struggling and putting on airs,
前途洋々なんて言えないね そんな良い言葉は
you can't call it smooth sailing with words like that.
殴り合いっこで
Just beating each other up.
さあ だだだだだだ 待て待て待て待て
Now, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait,
前途多難だ 前へよ
the future is full of trouble, move forward!
言えないないそんな良い言葉は
You can't say such nice words.
少しだけ静かにしてほしいね ああ 私たち待望へ
I want you to be a little quiet, ah, toward our long-awaited desire.
世界ででで 爆笑やんやんや
In the world, laughter yanyan-ya,
果たしてその日まで
until that very day.
らりるれ連呼やんやんや
Rarirure calling yanyan-ya,
あんたの真似にもやんやんや
even imitating you yanyan-ya.
世界ででで 狂おしやりやんや 空腹の血まで
In the world, madness yanyan-ya, right down to the hungry blood.
さあ かぎぎぎ 待って待って待って待って 僕やんやんや
Now, wait, wait, wait, wait, it's me yanyan-ya!
今日も今日とて ソッチのケで 家に寝るから 私一人でも やっておきますね
Today as usual, I'll ignore that and sleep at home, I can handle it even by myself.
すべてすべてすべて任せて それをさせてよ 私のことなの 分かっているでしょ
Leave everything, everything, everything to me, let me do it, you know it's about me, right?
宵の口十中八九で 面倒くさいま まぁ今日も明日も過ぎていくのでしょう
Troublesome nine times out of ten in the early night, well today and tomorrow will probably just pass by.
生きていてくれてありがとう
Thank you for being alive!
一緒に歌ってたやった
We sang together, yay!
やった！やった！
Yay! Yay!
芳べにニーズを上げましょう 時の中折れたこと忘れてた
Let's raise the needs, I forgot about breaking in the passage of time.
さあだだだだだ 待て待て待て待て 前途多難だ 前へよ 言えないないそんな良い言葉は
Now wait, wait, wait, wait, future is troubled, move forward, you can't say such nice words.
少しだけ静かにしてほしいね ああ 私たち待望へ
I want you to be a little quiet, ah, toward our long-awaited desire.
今まで未来 見たかったはずなのに
Even though I should have wanted to see the future until now.
世界ででで 爆笑やんやんや 見えぬその日まで
In the world, laughter yanyan-ya, until that invisible day.
どどどどど やんやんや この世の理は やんやんや
Dodo yanyan-ya, the reason of this world yanyan-ya.
今はぜぜぜ 狂され やんやんや 猛毒の血まで
Now madness yanyan-ya, right down to the deadly blood.
さあかぎぎぎ 待って待って待って待って 僕やんやんや
Now wait, wait, wait, wait, it's me yanyan-ya!
果たしてその日まで れれれれれ 連呼やんやんや あんたの真似にもやんやんや
Until that day, rerere calling yanyan-ya, even imitating you yanyan-ya.
世界ででで 狂おしやりやんや 狂おし並び でじのわいふを褒めましょう
In the world, madness yanyan-ya, let's praise our digital waife.
もういいじゃん 無気力になっちゃって
Forget it, becoming listless,
かっこつけて かっこよくない
putting on airs and not looking cool—
そういうの嫌になってんだ ほっといてよ
I'm sick of things like that, just leave me alone!
死にたくない もういいじゃん
I don't want to die, whatever!
やけになってんの 嫉妬したって
Becoming desperate, even if I get jealous,
嫉妬できない 聞こえないよう耳塞いだて
I can't feel jealousy, plugging my ears so I can't hear,
行ってくるしんどいな
here I go, it's so tough.
僕は誰も覗かないから 僕のことそっとしといて
I don't peer at anyone, so just leave me alone.
だから 僕のこと そっとしといて
So please just leave me be.
うざいだけのバカにははいはいはい
To the annoying idiots, yeah yeah yeah,
ウケる またねのお小遣い待ってるねだとか
hilarious, waiting for pocket money or whatever.
本当は怯えてる 吠えるだけの弱虫だだだ
Actually I'm terrified, just a barking coward.
痛い癖に耐えてはいはいはい
Enduring even though it hurts, yeah yeah yeah,
いつも平気なフリばっかなの
always acting like I'm totally fine.
僕は壁を張ったまま笑う それ以上近づかないで
I smile with a wall up, don't get any closer than that!
怖いじゃん
It's scary, you know.
ばか ばか ばか ばか ばか ばか やだ ばか ばか
Idiot, idiot, idiot, idiot, no, idiot!
もういいじゃん まだ怒ってんの
Forget it, are you still mad?
ほっといてよ ホッとなんてできない
Just leave me alone, I can't relax at all.
見えないように目を逸らしたって 付いてくるじゃん
Even if I look away so I can't see, you still follow me.
やっぱり
As expected.
転がったら起きればいいじゃん 失ったら探ればいいじゃん
If you fall, just get back up; if you lose something, just search for it!
それでよくない？ 間違ったら直せばいいじゃん
Isn't that fine? If you make a mistake, just fix it!
それってよくない？
Isn't that fine?
僕だって誰も望まないよ
Nobody really wants it either,
だったら僕のことそっとしといてやんないこと
so if you're not going to leave me alone,
全部大丈夫だって言えたらいいのにな 想えたらいいのにな
I wish I could just say everything's fine...
想えたらいいのにな
I wish I could feel that way...
本当は分かっていた
To be honest, I knew
いけないことだって分かっていたのに
I knew it was wrong, but still,
この手をすり抜ける全部が愛に見えたの
everything slipping through these hands looked like love.
確かめていた言葉が形になって
The words I made sure of take shape,
揺れるだけ 弾いて 描いて きっと それだけ
just swaying, strumming, drawing, that's all.
うわはは 歌いだけの馬鹿にハイハイハイ
Haha, yeah, yeah, to the singing idiot,
受ける まだ残してるねだとか 本当は怯えている
hilarious, still holding on, when I'm actually terrified.
吠えるだけの弱虫だったんだ 痛い口に耐えてハイハイハイ
Just a barking coward, enduring the painful remarks,
いつも 平気なふりばっかなの 僕は 壁を張ったまま笑う
always acting like I'm fine, smiling behind a wall.
壁を張ったまま笑う それ以上近づかないで
Smiling behind a wall. Don't come any closer—
本当まばっかばっかいい加減ばっか 飛んだばっか 脱せなくて
It's all nonsense, just escaping, can't break out...
そんな言葉っこともう僕もやっぱどうしようもないんだ
Words like that—I guess I'm helpless too.
天井界 したいのこと耐えてれないない 死ねるって僕も口ばっかでね
I can't take it anymore, saying I could die is all talk too.
今日も 壁を張ったまま笑う それ以上近づかないで
Today too, smiling behind a wall. Don't come any closer—
怖いじゃん ばかばっか ほら ばかばっか
it's scary, bunch of fools, look, a bunch of fools.
はい、ということで十大告知ライブ始まりました！皆さんまったかね！
So, the 10 major announcements live has begun! Hello everyone!
ホロックスの女幹部、鷹嶺ルイともします。ということでみんな見えとるぞ、コメント。
I'm Takane Lui, Holox's female executive. I can see your comments, everyone!
お、拍手いっぱいありがとな！拍手いっぱいありがと。
Oh, thank you so much for the applause! Thanks for all the cheers.
ということで、本日のハッシュタグはですね、こちら。
So, today's hashtag is right here.
ハッシュタグ鷹嶺ルイ重大告知ライブでたくさんつぶやいて...あ、つぶやきじゃないわ、ポストしてくれると嬉しいです！
Please post lots with #TakaneLuiMajorAnnouncementLive... Ah, not tweet, post! I'd be so happy if you do!
ということで1曲目、2曲目とオーバーロード、ばかばっかと熱い曲が続いたんですが、なんと1曲目から特別ゲストが登場してくれました！
So, we had hot songs like "Overdose" and "Bakabakka" for the 1st and 2nd songs, and amazingly, a special guest joined us right from the start!
ちょっとおしゃべりしたいと思いますので、呼びたいと思います！
We'd love to chat a bit, so let's call her out!
ワッサ！我らはコースわりの果てだ、えんどう！こりのにふねさいし、くろかれのばら なんじのともほろえの箱すペールです！
What's up! We are the edge of the course, and everything!
ということでBaeちゃんとはね、オーバーロードを一緒に歌わせていただいたんですけども！
So, Bae-chan and I got to sing "Overdose" together!
めっちゃ嬉しい！嬉しい、私も嬉しい！
Super happy! Happy, I'm happy too!
Baeちゃんとは本当にあの、一緒に歌いたくて…え、同じです！
Bae-chan and I really wanted to sing together... - Ah, same!
いやBaeねの曲めっちゃ好きなんで、ね！めっちゃかっこよくて、ようやく歌いマスターね！
I love Bae-ne's songs so much! They're so cool, and we finally got to sing it!
歌いましたね！ね、めっちゃ嬉しい！
We sang it! Right, super happy!
絶対Baeちゃんに合うと思って、やっぱカオスなんでね。
I thought it would totally fit Bae-chan, since it's so chaotic.
はははは！いや、めっっちゃかっこいい！
Hahaha! Man, it's super cool!
いや嬉しい、一緒に歌えて。ちょっとね、あの最後のとこ、ちょっとやらかした…
I'm so happy we sang together. Um, the ending part, I kind of messed up...
え、嘘！？全然分かんなかったよ、たぶん。
Eh, really?! I totally didn't notice, probably.
いや、たぶんね、振りはね…あ、言っていい、これ？振りはもともとなかったんだよね。
Well, you see, the choreography... Oh, can I say this? There wasn't any choreography originally.
で、なんかリハ中で、あ、ちょっと振り付けようか、みたいな話になってて、う、えー！やばい！で、ちょっと最後のとこ忘れちゃって、すいません。
Then during rehearsal we talked about adding some choreography, and I forgot the ending part, sorry!
いや全然わからなかった、でもやっぱさ、テンション上がっちゃうとね、わかる！
I totally didn't notice! But you know, when your tension goes up, I get it!
いやでも楽しんでくれたんだよね、きっとね。
But you enjoyed it, I'm sure.
めちゃくちゃ楽しかった！めちゃくちゃ楽しかった！
Super fun! It was insanely fun!
私もBaeちゃんの曲も本当に大好きで、いつかBaeちゃんの曲も挑戦したいななんて…ぜひぜひ聴きたい！
I really love Bae's songs too, I'd love to challenge one someday... - Oh, definitely wanna hear it!
一緒に歌ってくれますか？いやもうぜひです！
Will you sing with me? - Yes, absolutely!
いやBaeねの、最後聴きたいかも。最後ね！いや、最後難しいけど、え、ぜひ一緒に歌いましょう！
I wanna hear Bae-ne's... wait, the last part! It's hard, but let's sing it together!
歌いましょう！お願いします！おねが…なんだこれ？
Let's sing! Please! Plei— What is this?
ということで、21時半からですね、ごろ…あ、21時半頃にですね、十大告知を…
So, starting around 9:30 PM, we'll have the 10 major announcements...
十大告知をさせていただますので、もう少しお待ちいただけますと幸いです！
We'll be announcing the 10 major announcements, so we'd appreciate it if you could wait a little longer!
Big Announcement at 9:30 PM JST! ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
"Big announcement at 9:30 PM JST!" Thank you! Thank you a lot!
いや海外にもね、返事してくれるんじゃないかな？大丈夫かな？
I wonder if overseas viewers will reply too? Will they be okay?
ということで、この後はですね、事前収録で来ていただいたゲストさんのパートになりますので、一緒に、じゃあVTRのキュー振ってもらってもいいですか、Baeちゃん？
So after this, it's the guest part recorded in advance, so Bae-chan, can you cue the VTR together with me?
よし！それでは皆さん、この後も楽しんでいってください！せーの、VTRどうぞ！
Alright! Everyone, please enjoy the rest as well! Ready, set, roll VTR!
単純で明快で簡単じゃない
It's not simple, clear-cut, or easy
まだ想像と妄想と偏見で Why
Still with imagination, delusions, and prejudice, why
そりゃ完全な万全な設定じゃない
It's hardly a complete and foolproof setup
からかってくれないか
Won't you tease me?
外見と内面と偶像の不一致
Mismatch between appearance, inner self, and idol
この繊細さ敏感さ共有しよ
Let's share this delicacy and sensitivity
ほら冷静な表情は実際ちょーハイ
See, my calm expression is actually super high
見つけてくれないか
Won't you find me?
はいはいお姉さんしまっちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, big sis, let's pack it up and go
はいはい期待感背負っちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, carrying expectations, let's go
はいはいお姉さんしまっちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, big sis, let's pack it up and go
はいはい期待感背負っちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, carrying expectations, let's go
ホロホロホロホロホークだけど
Holo-holo-holo-holo-Hawk, but
高嶺の花みたいに扱っちゃ嫌
Don't treat me like an unattainable flower
あのね誰も彼も鷲と勘違い驚きの目(アイ)
Hey, everyone mistakes me for an eagle, eyes of surprise
ホロホロホロホロホークだけど
Holo-holo-holo-holo-Hawk, but
PONコツみがちょいあるだけで親近感
Just a bit of clumsiness gives a sense of closeness
その際その差異その才受け止めてよね
Accept that margin, difference, and talent
鷹嶺の未来乾杯
Toast to Takane's future
ノーイーグルしっかりウォッチ
No Eagle, watch closely
ノーイーグル曖昧 You Know
No Eagle, vague You Know
ノーイーグル狩りとか苦手
No Eagle, bad at hunting
ノーイーグル猛禽ルイ姉
No Eagle, raptor big sis Lui
ノーイーグル一見クールね
No Eagle, cool at first glance
ノーイーグル意外とギャップ系
No Eagle, surprisingly gap moe
ノーイーグルイメージ大変身
No Eagle, major image transformation
ノーイーグルOK?
No Eagle, OK?
大衆の歓声って内蔵じゃない？
Isn't the roar of the crowd like internal organs?
ありゃ心配ね相談ね散々ねもう
Oh dear, worries, consultations, plenty already
ただ正論や暴論の配信じゃない！
This isn't a stream of just right or absurd theories!
個人的見解だ正解
My personal opinion is the correct answer
ホロホロホロホロホークだけど
Holo-holo-holo-holo-Hawk, but
捕食しないさだから怖がっちゃ嫌
I won't prey on you, so don't be scared
ほらね爪も羽も お洒落に研いで隠しちゃいない
Claws and wings sharpened stylishly, not hiding them
ホロホロホロホロホークだけど
Holo-holo-holo-holo-Hawk, but
観察眼がちょいあるだけで緊張感
Just a bit of observation creates tension
その際その差異その才受け止めよね
Accept that margin, difference, and talent
鷹まる時代乾杯
Toast to the soaring era
はいはいお姉さんしまっちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, big sis, let's pack it up and go
はいはい期待感背負っちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, carrying expectations, let's go
はいはいお姉さんしまっちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, big sis, let's pack it up and go
はいはい期待感背負っちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, carrying expectations, let's go
ホロホロホロホロホークだけど
Holo-holo-holo-holo-Hawk, but
高嶺の花みたいに扱っちゃ嫌
Don't treat me like an unattainable flower
あのね誰も彼も鷲と勘違い驚きの目(アイ)
Hey, everyone mistakes me for an eagle, eyes of surprise
ホロホロホロホロホークだけど
Holo-holo-holo-holo-Hawk, but
PONコツみがちょいあるだけで親近感
Just a bit of clumsiness gives a sense of closeness
その際その差異その才受け止めてよね
Accept that margin, difference, and talent
鷹嶺の未来乾杯 愛じゃん
Toast to Takane's future, it's love
鷹まる時代乾杯
Toast to the soaring era
まがまがう魔眼ウィング
Magan Wing
Sorry to be late
Do you remember me?
魅了する目と目が合ったらきっとはがすんだ
If our captivating eyes meet, I'll surely tear them away
足ない爪はもう魔鷹かだ
Not enough claws are already demonic hawks
それは Wink off Wink off いつだってずっと Trick or Treat
That is Wink off Wink off always Trick or Treat
I'm Crazyな台風の目
I'm the eye of a crazy typhoon
目に入れて痛くないくらい
So precious it wouldn't hurt to put in my eye
なにげなく口ばしに Sweet Vengeance
Casually with Sweet Vengeance on my beak
憎しみならとっくに捨てた
Grudges were thrown away long ago
怖がってんの？ あっそ
Are you scared? Oh, I see
Don't let me down, Eyes on me now
まだまだ遊ばなきゃ
We still need to play
安全じゃないから？健全じゃないから？
Because it's not safe? Because it's not wholesome?
それがなんだ Franticだね
So what, it's frantic
目には目を
An eye for an eye
Say La La La 靡け零れ落ちた君
Say La La La, flutter, you who overflowed
Say Liar Liar Liar まっ赤っ赤だ
Say Liar Liar Liar, it's bright red
Oh EYE EYE EYE Want you de vibe
バイバイアンサー
Bye-bye, answer
怨嗟
Resentment
目に見物見せる
A sight to behold
My EYE EYE
Wink off
瞳よ
Eyes...
目を眩む半分ね
Half-blinded and dazzled,
掠奪ウィンク
A plundering wink
有能が如く絢爛降臨
Brilliant descent like a prodigy
魔眼ウィンク
Evil-eye wink
My god
ほらご覧 瞬く間に
Look, in the blink of an eye,
EYE EYE EYE
EYE'll kill you
wink
後ろ指 差したいなら お好きにどうぞ
If you want to point fingers behind my back, go right ahead
東奔西走 振り返らぬ諸行無常の金輪際
Rushing east and west, the unyielding fleeting limit
お待たせ Suck out Sukou
Sorry to keep you waiting, suck out, sukou
おさらば乱ミココ Cut Cut
Farewell, chaos miko, cut cut
無礼講な堕落の目
A shameless, depraved eye
I'm coming back
目じゃない感情にない
Not an eye, without emotion
最善じゃないだろう 最良じゃないだろう
It's not the best, is it? It's not optimal!
それがどうしたんだ Franticだね
So what if it is? How frantic
目には目を 歯には羽を
An eye for an eye, a wing for a tooth
La La La
C'est la la vie
ああ ルイは何を呼ぶ?
Ah, what does Lui summon?
C'est la la vie 羽ばたきを走るウィンク
C'est la la vie, a wink racing through the wings
目が離せない 完璧なウィンク
A gaze you can't tear away, a perfect wink
セラララビセキュララキミエンウィンク セララライヤマッ赤かな
C'est la la vie, secure la ki-mi en wink, c'est la la vie, deep red
Oh EYE EYE EYE I want you de
Oh EYE EYE EYE I want you, yeah
バイバイアンサー
Bye-bye answer
怨嗟
Resentment
目に見物見せる
A sight to behold
My EYE EYE
Wink off
もう目が離せない EYE EYE 魔眼ウィンク
Now I can't look away, EYE EYE, evil-eye wink
引けない
You can't back down
なんテナリエナイ
How could that be?
後に引けない
Can't back down now
無闇にひけらかさない Fly
Don't flaunt it recklessly, fly
いつもと突然のハラハラ 火花散らしでばいのおちからから
Always suddenly thrilling, sparks flying with power
まったなし媚びずダンシング
No waiting, dancing without pandering
猛烈だからステップで交わしちゃうぜ
It's fierce, so let's exchange steps and have fun
サラリーな社会が眠るころに
When the salaryman society falls asleep
パラリラ夜から爆走するコロニー
A colony roaring through the paralyzing night
もちつもたれず表裏一体をくぐり抜けて
Navigating two sides of the same coin without relying on each other
平日はShoo be doo be do
Weekdays are Shoo be doo be do
週末もShoo be doo be do
Weekends are Shoo be doo be do
時につくハードに時に平穏のバドに今宵ひみつのおしごと
Sometimes hitting hard, sometimes calm, tonight is a secret job
煌々煌々と狙ってバババーン 外さないクリア
Glittering brightly, aiming, bang bang, never missing, clear
意気揚々目立ってランアンドガン
Triumphant, standing out, run and gun
未だに他に類を見ない
Unseen anywhere else still
意気揚々迫ってバババーン 悟られずカバー
Triumphant, closing in, bang bang, covered without being noticed
Here we go yo 気取ってさあ出番 跡を濁さず
Here we go yo, putting on airs, now it's our turn, leave no trace
決して逃がさない もう一度希望をぬくまで
Never let you escape, until extracting every last hope
決して怪我さない 守る胸の看板
Never get hurt, protecting the sign on our chests
気取れないれんまわり お見舞いする後の祭り Oh yeah
Unpretentious turns, the aftermath visit, Oh yeah
響くヒールのお音が お仕置きの合図 誰も彼もチクタクホークアイ
The echoing heels signal punishment; hawk-eye ticking away
年始からShoo be doo be do 年末もShoo be doo be do
From New Year's Shoo be doo be do to year-end Shoo be doo be do
おまかせあれハンドリング 表に出せない後処理 もといひみつのおしごと
Leave handling to us, secret post-processing, a secret job
煌々煌々と狙ってバババーン 外さないクリア
Glittering brightly, aiming, bang bang, never missing, clear
意気揚々目立ってランアンドガン しばししらぬいは友を呼ぶ
Triumphant, standing out, run and gun, birds of a feather flock together
意気揚々迫ってバババーン 悟られずカバー
Triumphant, closing in, bang bang, covered without being noticed
Here we go yo 気取ってさあ出番 爪を剥き出し
Here we go yo, putting on airs, now it's our turn, baring claws
厄介企業をもどきて 乱れ踊るのなら
If you're brushing aside troublesome corporations and dancing wildly
枷が外れて容赦できなくなって やば爆裂
Shackles come off, showing no mercy, oh no, explosion!
ぼやき悲し弱音なんてすぐねんね 混じりけないハートビート 揺らすこの世界
Complaining and whining go to sleep! Unadulterated heartbeat
最果てまで届こう鳴らした鐘 裏の裏までいただいたりじゃおう
The bell ringing to reach the ends of the earth, taking deep secrets
煌々煌々と狙ってバババーン 外さないクリア
Glittering brightly, aiming, bang bang, never missing, clear
意気揚々目立ってランアンドガン 未だに他に類を見ない
Triumphant, standing out, run and gun, unseen anywhere else
意気揚々迫ってバババーン 悟られずカバー
Triumphant, closing in, bang bang, covered without being noticed
Here we go yo 気取ってさあ出番 跡を濁さず Take off
Here we go yo, putting on airs, leave no trace, Take off
今日も秘密のTake off
Today's secret takeoff...
迷子のこの華麗にどうも
Hello to this lost, gorgeous self...
冷えた冷えた手で
with my cold, cold hands,
信じられるものは自分だけだと想い込んで進み続けて
believing only in myself and pushing ever onward.
あの娘みたいにすれば君じゃそれは無理だ
If you try to be like her, for you that's impossible—
言わせとけばいいさ
so just let them talk!
たった一人 逆境の先 愛着からバーガセイ
All alone, beyond adversity, goodbye to attachment...
私の邪魔させやしない
I won't let anyone get in my way!
煌びやかで見据えた神
Looking down from my dazzling height, the god I set my sights on...
愛なくなくの空へ 飛んでいく私を見ないなんて
Flying into the loveless sky, how can you not look at me?
Bye-bye!
失敗は止まった時 今日も挑み合っての
When failure stops, today too, challenging each other,
君の無いものはないと
you have everything—
信じられるものを 見つけ出すまでと泣いたって
crying until I find something I can believe in,
笑い飛ばすんだ
I'll laugh it all off!
あの娘はもう終わりだ これ以上はないね
That girl is already finished, there's no more than this—
言わせとけばいいさ
so just let them talk!
一人の祈りだって 醒めても夢見てて大歓声
Even a solitary prayer, waking from it, dreaming to a huge ovation—
私はここで死にたくない
I don't want to die here!
一生の旅 逆境の先 愛着からバーガセイ
The journey of a lifetime, beyond adversity, goodbye to attachment...
私の邪魔させやしない
I won't let anyone get in my way!
煌びやかで見据えた神 愛なくなくの空へ
Looking down from my dazzling height, flying into the loveless sky,
飛んでいく私を見ないなんて
how can you not look at me?
Bye-bye!
誰かに言われなくたって
Even if no one tells me,
私のほうがもっと嫌いだ
I hate myself even more.
うるさいな
How annoying...
想像が視界を塞いで
Imaginations block my vision,
惨めな理由を書き連ねる
writing down miserable reasons.
教室にずっと居残り
Staying behind in the classroom,
窓の向こうに黒い影があって
there was a black shadow beyond the window,
何も言わずにこっちを見ていた
looking this way without saying a word.
私は貴方に救われたくて
I wanted to be saved by you,
泣くんじゃない
so don't cry—
産声は止められないもの
a first cry is something you cannot stop.
何千回ともう一度死に損なおう
Thousands of times over, let's fail to die once more.
希望と絶望の夜中を纏って
Enveloped in the dead of night, of hope and despair,
醜い光を許したいのは
the one who wants to forgive this ugly light
他ならない私だった
was none other than myself.
息をして
Breathe,
目を開けて
open your eyes—
これが最後かどうか
whether this is the very last time
知る術はないよ 知りたくもないよ
I have no way of knowing, nor do I want to know.
優しいな 懇々と闇は寄り添って
How kind, the darkness nestles close, trickling on,
溶けない答えを塗り潰し
painting over answers that won't melt away...
誰にも言われなくたって
Even if no one tells me,
私の方がもっと嫌いだ
I hate myself even more.
うるさいな
So noisy.
想像が視界を塞いで 惨めな理由を書き連ねる
Imagination blocks my vision, writing down miserable reasons.
教室にずっと居残り 窓の向こうに黒い影があって 何も言わずにこっちを見ていた
Staying in the classroom until the end, a black shadow watched me silently from across the window.
私は貴方に救われたくて 泣くんじゃない
I'm not crying because I want you to save me.
産声は止められないもの
The first cry is something I cannot stop.
何千回ともう一度死に損なおう 希望と絶望の夜中を纏え
Let me fail to die again, thousands of times, draped in the midnight of hope and despair.
何千回ともう一度死に損なおう
Let me fail to die again, thousands of times,
希望と絶望の夜中を纏え
draped in the midnight of hope and despair.
息をして 目をあけて
Breathe and open your eyes,
これが最後かどうか
I don't know if this is the end.
知る術はないよ 知りたいともないよ
I don't even want to know.
優しいな 昏々と闇は寄り添って
So gentle, the darkness snuggled up closely, drowsily.
醜い光を愛せたとき 終わらせなかった産声を...
When I can love the ugly light, let me turn the first cry I couldn't stop...
謳にしよう
Into a song.
特報
[Breaking News]
戦う理由は、一つじゃない
The reasons to fight are not just one.
Lapislazuli
Lapis Lazuli
25.12.03
2025.12.03
全国CDショップにて予約開始！
Pre-orders available at CD shops nationwide!
ゲーマーズにてリリース記念ミニライブ開催決定！
Release commemorative mini-live at Gamers!
Stay Tuned.
はい、ということで、
Yes, so,
いま特報を見ていただきましたが、
you've just seen the special report, but
なんと！鷹嶺ルイ、12月3日に
incredibly! Takane Lui, on December 3rd,
自身のセカンドアルバム『Lapis Lazuli』を発売することが決定しましたーー！わーーい！いえーーい！
will release her 2nd album "Lapis Lazuli"! Yay! Woohoo!
ということで、なんとですね、今回は鷹嶺ルイ初のアニメ全国、全国のショップで買える全国流通盤ということで、
So, amazingly, this is Takane Lui's first nationally distributed album available at shops across Japan.
えーまた一つ夢が叶っちゃいました！みんなのおかげです、ありがとう！
Another dream has come true! Thanks to everyone, thank you!
えー、ファーストに続きまして、リバティに続きましてセカンドなんですけども、
Following the first and Liberty, this is the second,
今回は『Lapis Lazuli』というね、タイトルを付けさせていただきました。
and this time we've titled it "Lapis Lazuli".
この『Lapis Lazuli』というのはですね、いつもあのアルバムにはLの文字がついてるんですけれども、
As for "Lapis Lazuli", my albums always have the letter L,
えー今回もLの文字から始まるLapis Lazuliという言葉で、えーこちらですね、あの意味がですね、えー成功に導くだったりとか、
and this time it starts with L too. The word Lapis Lazuli means guiding to success,
あとのは結構あの、勝利へと、勝利を掴み取るみたいな、えー、意味合いが込められておりまして、
and also has implications of seizing victory.
なんとこちらアルバムはですね、VS戦いをテーマにした曲になっております、あ、曲が、曲ばかりになっておりますので、
This album's songs are entirely themed around "VS battles",
えー、そういった意味合いも込めて、
so incorporating those meanings,
えーラピスラズリという名前をつけさせていただきました！さらになんとですね、
we named it Lapis Lazuli! Furthermore, incredibly,
秋葉原ゲーマーズ本店さんでも、リリース記念ライブをやらせていただくことになりました！イエーイ！
we'll be holding a release commemorative live at Akihabara Gamers main store! Yay!
なんとミニライブも開催ということで、えー本日ですね、えー12時半から予約開始となっているので、もうすでに、えー予約ができる状態になっております。
There's also a mini-live! Pre-orders start today at 12:30, so you can already pre-order right now.
えー皆さんも見えますかね？ 画面の左下、左下にボタンありますか？
Can everyone see it? Is there a button on the bottom left of the screen?
みんなある？ボタン？
Does everyone have it? A button?
そこからですね、購入ボタンがありますので、そこから予約ができるようになりましたのでぜひぜひこちらから予約してみてください！
There's a purchase button there, so you can make your pre-orders from there, please check it out!
ということで、アルバムの詳細をね、えー、バッとお話しさせていただこうかなと思うんですが、おめでとうありがとみんな！
Now, I'd like to quickly go over the album details. Congratulations and thank you everyone!
えー、収録曲についてはこちらになります。トゥデム！
As for the tracklist, here it is. Ta-da!
はい、えー先行リリースしておりますジグザグを始め、えー先ほども言いましたVS戦いをテーマにした全10曲が収録されています。
Starting with the pre-released "ZIG-ZAG", all 10 tracks themed around VS battles are included.
えー6曲目にはですね、皆さんお分かりですか？フューチャリングラプラスダークネスということで、
For the 6th track, featuring Laplace Darkness,
10曲目の「抗う君へのレクイエム」という曲はですね
Also, the 10th track, "Requiem for You Who Fight,"
とあるアニメのイメージソングになっておりますので
is inspired by a certain anime,
これから色々情報が出てくると思いますので
so various information will be coming out.
楽しみに待っていただければなと思います。
I hope you look forward to it.
そして、完全生産限定版はこんな感じになっております。どうぞ！
And here is the complete limited edition version!
お、どうぞ。あ、こっちだ。どうぞ、あ、こっちだ。
There we go. Ah, this way.
スライドボックス式でですね、あの、2人の鷹嶺ルイを、あの、離したりくっつけたりできる。
It uses a slide box where you can slide or attach the two Takane Luis together.
おしゃれでしょ？
Pretty stylish, right?
しかもリバティと同じ、ソラニさんが、え、イラストを担当してくださいました。
And SOLANI-san handled the illustrations, just like with Liberty!
めちゃくちゃかっこよくないですか？
Isn't it super cool?
ぜひぜひね、あの、戦わせたり話したりして、遊んでみてください。
Please, please, you know, make them fight or talk and play with them!
他にもこのようなグッズもございます。
There are also other goods like this.
完全生産限定版にはですね、え、今までのリリースした楽曲のジャケットを、え、入れ込んだジャケットイラストブック、これね、私が欲しいて言ったんですよ。
The complete limited edition includes a jacket illustration book containing the jackets of all previously released songs—I actually asked for this!
え、そしたらね、む、無理やり欲しいて言ったんですけど、
And when I said I desperately wanted it,
なんと実現をして下さりまして、今までの、え、リリースした楽曲のジャケットが1冊の本になって見れるやつになっております。
they actually made it happen so you can see all previous song jackets in a single book!
いや、みんな欲しかったっしょ？
Everyone wanted this, right?
いや、私が欲しいものはきっとみんなが欲しいと思いまして、え、こちらちょっとむりやり作っていただきました。
I figured what I wanted, everyone else would want too, so I went ahead and forced them to make it!
ご協力してくださったあの関係者の皆さんありがとうございます。
Thank you to all the related staff who cooperated.
そしてですね、オリジナル缶バッチも2種類ついて、そしてそして今回もですね、完全生産限定版にだけになるんですけど、直筆サイン入りジャケットカードを、購入者全員皆様に、え、直筆サインさせていただきますので、
And furthermore, exclusive to the complete limited edition, every single purchaser will receive a hand-signed jacket card with a hand-written comment!
ぜひぜひ完全生産限定版、色んな特典がありますので買って頂けますと幸いでございます。
So please do grab the complete limited edition with all its special bonuses!
さらに通常版はこちら。
And here is the regular edition.
はい。通常版にはですね、ランダムアナザージャケット、え、1枚入り、え、全5種類ある中の1枚が入っております。
The regular edition comes with 1 random anather jacket out of 5 variations.
そしてこちらもですね、数量限定ランダムで鷹嶺ルイの直筆サイン、そしてコメントも付いてきます。直筆ココメントも付いてきます。
And this also comes with a randomly included hand-written signature and comment!
ちょっとこちらはランダムになっちゃうんですけども、ぜひぜひ、あ、皆さんに当たりますように。通常版もぜひ買ってみてください。
So please make sure to grab the regular edition too!
そしてそして各ショップの、え、法人特典はこちらになります。とどん。
And here are the store-specific bonuses.
アマゾン様マウスパッドだったりいろいろなね、え、お店でいろんな特典がついておりますので、みなさん欲しいものがあればそちらで予約してくださると嬉しいでございます。
From Amazon's mouse pads to various other stores offering different bonuses, please check them out and reserve whichever one catches your eye!
また詳細などは、え、ポストしますので、そちらで詳しく見ていってください。
Further details will be posted later, so please check those out for more info.
え、先ほどもお伝えしました秋葉原ゲーマーズ本店さんにて12月7日にリリース記念ミニライブの開催が決定しましたーー！
As mentioned earlier, a release commemorative mini-live has been decided at Akihabara Gamers main store on December 7th!
ゲーマーズさんでアルバムを購入した人の中から抽選でミニライブにご招待をさせていただきます。
We will invite lucky winners selected from everyone who purchases the album at Gamers to the mini-live!
ぜひゲーマーズさんでもアルバムを買ってくださると嬉しいでございます。
We'd be thrilled if you buy the album at Gamers as well!
ということで、え、今回ですね、あの、皆さんの左下にあるボタンではですね、完全生産限定版と通常版のところにECサイトに飛ぶのかな？
Now, clicking the button on the bottom left will take you to the official site for both the complete limited and regular editions,
多分オフィシャルサイトに飛びますので、え、皆さんそちらで完全生産限定版、版だったりとかが欲しいよっていう方はそちらで予約をしていただきまして、ちょっと他の、え、ショップさんで予約をしたいよという方はね、あの、詳細後ほど、あの、Xそして概要欄にも貼らせていただきますので、そちらね、チェックをしていただけると嬉しいでございます。
so if you want the complete limited edition, you can pre-order there, and for other shops, we'll post details on X and in the description later!
いやラピスラズリ、しかもですね、ちょっとラピスラズリって、あの、誕生月、誕生席？
And Lapis Lazuli's release months are September and December—
が9月と12月ということでなんと9月に私10大発表をして、え、12月に発売っていうね
Wait, September for the 10th-anniversary announcement and December for the release!
あ、これたまたまなんですけど、あ、まあたまたまて言わない方がいいよね。あ、これね、あの、あの、仕掛けなんですね、これ。仕掛けさせていただきました。
Ah, this is just a coincidence—well, actually, I planned it!
偶然、偶然じゃなくてちゃんと考え、ちゃんと、ちゃんと考えました。
It wasn't a coincidence, I really thought it through!
ました全国流通版のセカンドアルバムぜひぜひ皆さんご購入いただけますと幸いです。
We're releasing our second nationwide album, and I'd be so happy if you all could purchase it!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you so much for your support!
それではまだまだ歌っていきたいと思います。
Now then, I'd like to keep on singing.
このあともまだまだ告知がございますのでお楽しみに。
There are still more announcements coming up after this, so please look forward to it.
ちょっとお水飲んでもいいですか?
Do you mind if I have some water?
お水飲んでもいいですね。
I'll have some water, alright.
お水飲みます。
I'll drink some water.
ちょっと待ってください。
Just a moment, please.
飲みました。
I drank some!
ということでまだお一人えゲストが出てない方がいらっしゃいますね。その方はいつ出るんでしょうか?
With that said, there's still one guest who hasn't appeared yet. When will that person be coming out, I wonder?
お見逃しなくということで続いての曲行きましょうか。皆さん準備は大丈夫ですか?
Don't miss it! With that, shall we move on to the next song? Is everyone ready?
準備は大丈夫ですね。それでは
You're ready, right? Well then...
はいそれでは聞いてください。ジグザグ
Yes, then please listen to this: "ZIG-ZAG".
ワン・ツー・スリー・フォー
One, two, three, four!
ということでもう一人の特別ゲストを呼びたいと思います！
With that, I'd like to invite our special guest!
星街すいせい！盛り上がっていきましょう！
Hoshimachi Suisei! Let's get hyped!
『幸せ?』って囁いた
Whispering, "Are you happy?"
トラッタラッタラッタ
Tra-ta-la-ta-la-ta,
纏りついて離れんわダメドラッタラッタラッタ
Clinging on and won't let go, no good, tra-ta-la-ta-la-ta.
無味無臭の生活が思い出せないや
I can't even remember life without any taste or smell.
忘れたいから歌った馬鹿だラッタラッタラッタ
So I sang because I want to forget, what a fool, tra-ta-la-ta-la-ta.
恨むことも憎むことも賢くない
It's not wise to hold grudges or harbor hatred,
言えでいなかったこれが君の結末ならば
and I couldn't even say that. If this is your end,
笑ってしまいたいほど嘘嘘嘘「嘘つき」
I want to smile so much it's all lies, lies, lies—"Liars."
やだ痛い痛い痛い痛いな奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
No, it hurts, hurts, hurts, wishing just a little for miracles and such,
もう嫌嫌嫌嫌嫌!たちが悪いわ
I'm so sick of it, sick of it all! You've got a bad attitude.
ねぇ辛いlie lie lie否?おかしいとこ全部剥ぎ取って
Hey, painful lie, lie, lie. No? Strip away all the weird parts,
薄情で結構好きに呼んでいいよ
I don't care if you call me coldhearted as you please.
虎視狼々にバイバイしたいのデ・ス・テ・テ・デ・ス
I want to say bye-bye to pouncing wolves, de-su, te-te, de-su!
私、甘え上手になれなかった可愛げとかが足りなかった
I couldn't become good at depending on others, I lacked cuteness and charm.
後悔がうるさい夜だ
It's a night noisy with regrets.
過去は過去だと割り切っちゃえば?きっといいことあるさとかそれくらい百も承知だラッタラッタラッタ
"Just write off the past as the past?" I'm fully aware of things like that, tra-ta-la-ta-la-ta.
願うことも祈ることも許されないから黒く染めた元の色も思い出せない絡んだ運命の糸糸糸糸
Wishing and praying aren't allowed, so I dyed it black and can't even remember its original color, tangled threads of fate...
やだ痛い痛い痛い痛いな悲劇のヒロイン気取っちゃって
No, it hurts, hurts, hurts, playing the heroine of a tragedy,
もう嫌嫌嫌嫌嫌!諦めちえば?でも会いたいタイタイタイな
I'm so sick of it, sick of it all! Why not just give up? But I want to see you so badly,
思考回路がこんがらがっちゃって明日またきっと壊すけどいいの
my thought circuits get all tangled up. I'll surely break it again tomorrow, but that's fine.
トラウマさえ愛おしいのですで・す・て・て・で・す
Even the trauma is dear to me, de-su, te-te, de-su!
虎視狼々にバイバイしたいのデ・ス・テ・テ・デ・ス
I want to say bye-bye to pouncing wolves, de-su, te-te, de-su!
夢の中で君と手を繋いでいるの何も知らないあの頃の二人のままで
In my dream, I'm holding hands with you, staying just like the two of us back then knowing nothing.
でも分かっているよすぐに醒めてしまうとそれならばいっそ
But I know it will wake up soon. If that's the case, then rather...
君の手でそっと止め刺してほれ今今今!
Gently deliver the final blow with your hands, come on, right now, now, now!
やだ痛い痛い痛い痛いな奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
No, it hurts, hurts, hurts, wishing just a little for miracles and such,
もう嫌嫌嫌嫌嫌!たちが悪いわ
I'm so sick of it, sick of it all! You've got a bad attitude.
ねぇ辛いlie lie lie否?おかしいとこ全部剥ぎ取って
Hey, painful lie, lie, lie. No? Strip away all the weird parts,
薄情で結構好きに呼んでいいよ
I don't care if you call me coldhearted as you please.
虎視狼々にバイバイしたいのデ・ス・テ・テ・デ・ス・デ・ス・デ・ス
I want to say bye-bye to pouncing wolves, de-su, te-te, de-su, de-su, de-su!
すいちゃん来てくれてありがとう！いやあスイちゃん楽しかったぜ！いやあ嬉しいぜ！
Suichan, thank you for coming! Man, Suichan, that was so fun! I'm so happy!
ジグザグジグザグジグザグジグザグジグザグ
Zig-zag, zig-zag, zig-zag, zig-zag, zig-zag!
うわ！ということで皆さんにすいちゃんが来てくれました！
Wow! With that, Suichan came to join us everyone!
来ましたよ！
I came!
すいちゃんのことだからね、たぶんね、バチャライブの星街すいせいで、すいちゃんは今日もかわいい！ありがとうございます！
Knowing Suichan, she'd probably say: "It's Hoshimachi Suisei of VACHALIVE, and Suichan is cute today too!" Thank you so much!
ということで、ルイ、セカンドアルバム発売決定おめでとう！
And with that, Lui, congratulations on deciding to release your second album!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
いっぱい、あの、
I consulted them a lot...
いっぱい、はい、相談しました。
A lot, yes, I consulted with them.
いっぱい、いっぱい。確かに。Suichanも聞いたかも。
A lot, a lot. That's true. Suichan might have heard it too.
なんか曲、結構散ってるかも。
Some of the songs might be quite scattered.
そう、いっぱい、いっぱい相談しました、Suiちゃんに。
That's right, I consulted Sui-chan a lot.
この「ジグザグ」もね、実は…ちょっと、そう、リリース前から聞いてて。
And this 'Zigzag', actually... I'd been listening to it even before the release.
はい。はい。
Yes. Yes.
今日、そう、今日はですね、「ジグザグ」をSuiちゃんと歌いたかった理由はですね、
Today, yes, today... the reason I wanted to sing 'Zigzag' with Sui-chan is,
まあ、本当に、あの…歌い、あの…
well, really, um... to sing, um...
いっぱい、いっぱい相談をしたっていうのと、うん、うん。
because I consulted a ton about it, yeah, yeah.
あと、曲がね、あの…タイトルを一緒にね、考えてくれたんですよね、「ジグザグ」という。
And also, for the song, she helped me think of the title together, 'Zigzag'.
そうなんですよう！一番最初タイトル本当は違ったんだよね。
That's right! The very first title was actually different.
そう、そうなんですよう。
Yes, that's right.
うん、そこからどうかなつって、「えっ、ジグザグって、
Um, from there, we wondered what to do. 'Eh, doesn't zigzag...
トラウマって意味あるらしいよ？」みたいな。
...mean trauma?' or something.
なって、一緒にね、え、ジグザグ良くない？」みたいな。「地味じゃない？」
'And then, together, like, 'Isn't zigzag good?' 'Isn't it plain?'
みたい「間にお菓子とか入れようぜ！」え、「おしゃれじゃない？」みたいに。
'Like, 'Let's put snacks in between!' 'Isn't it stylish?'
そう、言ったんですよね。でね、たくさん、たくさん相談をしまして。
That's what we said, right? So we consulted a lot, a lot.
でね、ジグザグ、Suiちゃんに愛想だなぁ、みたいな。
And then, 'Zigzag feels like a love consultation to Sui-chan', or something.
いや、でもこれね、歌っててね…楽しいね。
Yeah, but singing this... is so fun.
楽しい！楽しいでしょ？いや、これ楽しいんですよ、すごく。
Fun! Isn't it fun? No, this is really fun, definitely.
で、しかも、ルイとね、やっぱ、その…高音質というかさ、この、なんだろ、低音歌う組というか。
And what's more, with Lui, you know, that vocal quality, or rather, the group that sings low notes, you could say.
そして、なんか、合ってるなっていうのもすごい思ったし、だから歌ってて楽しかったです。
And also, I really felt like we matched well, so it was fun to sing.
いや、もうジグザグ歌うんならSuiちゃんと歌いたいって言って、もう絶対Suiちゃんと歌うって言って。
I mean, if I'm gonna sing 'Zigzag', I wanna sing it with Sui-chan, I said, I'm definitely gonna sing it with Sui-chan.
でね、あの、呼び出したら快諾をしてくださいました。本当にお忙しい中ありがとうございます。
And you know, when I called her up, she readily agreed. Thank you so much despite your busy schedule.
いや、そんなのもうね、生出演、なんかいっつもだよ、出ちゃうんだよ。
No way, always appearing live like this, you always show up!
ありがとうございます！もうコメントの皆さんもね。
Thank you very much! And everyone in the comments too.
「はい、どうもどうも」「あ、いい、かっこいい、かっこいい、合ってる合ってる、わかるわかる」ってほらね、言ってるね。
'Yes, hello hello', 'Ah, nice, cool, cool, it fits, it fits, I get it, I get it', see, they're saying that.
いやあ、本当に一緒に歌えて、本当には緊張したんだけども、一緒に歌えてよかった。
Man, I was really nervous getting to sing together, but I'm glad we did.
しかも、2回目なんですね、一緒にお二人で歌ったの。そうなんですよね。
Plus, this is the second time the two of us sang together. That's right.
そうなんです。Mだでのファーストでね、バグ。そう、バグで。
That's right. For M.D.'s first, you know, 'Bug'. That's right, 'Bug'.
今度はジグザグ。ジグザグ。
This time it's 'Zigzag'. 'Zigzag'.
次は何になるんでしょうか？次は何グですか？何グになるんでしょうか？
What will the next one be? What kind of '-gu' will it be? What '-gu' will it turn into?
あのね、今後も楽しみにしていただけたらなと思うんですけれども、なんとまだ告知があるんです。
Well, I hope you'll look forward to it in the future, but there is still an announcement.
えっ、そんなまさか！
Eh, no way!
はい。なので、えっ？えっ？どんなやつ？
Yes. So, eh? Eh? What kind of thing?
え、ちょっと、この、このアルバムに絡めたやつですよ。
Eh, hold on, it's something tied to this album.
ええ！？なに、なに！？気になる、気になる！
Ehh!? What, what!? I'm curious, I'm curious!
じゃあ一緒に見ようか。
Then let's watch it together.
えっ、見るんだ。
Eh, we're watching it.
じゃあ、さ、一緒に見よ。はい。ということで、こちらをご覧ください。どうぞ。
Well, then, let's watch together. Yes. With that said, please take a look at this. Here you go.
誰だ 誰？ そちら様 どちら様？ はて さて と
Who's that? Who? Which one? Which one? Well now...
どん突き上げな
Pushing right up to the end,
絵は
the picture is
フーアーユー？ ハハウーユー？ お元気で一足お先に
Who are you? How are you? I'll be going ahead in good health
てか フーアーユー？
I mean, who are you?
昨日のジブンが描いた円からはみ出さないように
So you don't step outside the circle drawn by yesterday's self,
ひとはまり小さな円を描くような
drawing a slightly smaller circle once over,
ボールのバウンドが少しずつ低くなる様を
watching helplessly as the ball's bounce gets lower and lower,
術もなく眺めているような気分でしょ？ アハ
feeling like you have no choice? Aha.
ところでアナタ
By the way, you,
誰？ 誰？ 誰？ (え、誰？)
Who? Who? Who? (Eh, who?)
誰？ 誰？ 誰？ (誰？ 誰？)
Who? Who? Who? (Who? Who?)
おや はて さて
Oh, well now,
存じ上げないわ
I don't know you at all.
フーアーユー ユー ユー ユー どちら様？
Who are you, you, you, you, which one are you?
face to face コンニチハ
Face to face, hello.
ユー は ミー？ もーなんてたって
You are me? Well, whatever the case,
upside down for ジブン ジブン
upside down for self, self.
look alike 雷雨 落雷
Look alike, rainstorm, lightning strike.
このあとOriginal Anime MV公開！
[Original Anime MV releasing next!]
なんとセカンドアルバムより、誰か本日24時に先行デジタルリリースがされます！
And from the second album, an early digital release by someone will be out today at 24:00!
誰！？ 誰誰誰！？
Who!? Who who who!?
え、こっちのルイはわかるけど、こっちのルイは誰！？
Eh, I know this Lui on this side, but who is the Lui on this other side!?
誰なんだろう？
Who could it be?
え、気になるよね。気になるね。
Eh, I'm curious. I'm curious.
実はこの曲作った人も気にならない？え、気になる！
Actually, aren't you curious about who made this song too? Eh, I'm curious!
なんと、マガンウィンクを作ってくれたてにをはさんが今回も作せしてくれたよ！
And amazingly, teniwoha, who made 'Magan Wink', composed this one for us again!
あー！てにをは節、確かに感じる！感じる感じる、めちゃ感じる。
Ah! I can definitely feel the teniwoha style! I feel it, I feel it so much.
そして、この配信終了、終了、あ、終了後に、MVが公開されます！
And then, after this stream ends—ends, ah—after it ends, the MV will be released!
わあ！MVさっき流れてたやつですか？
Wow! Is that the MV that was playing just now?
そうなんです、なんと、あの、鷹嶺ルイ史上、今回鷹嶺ルイ史上いっぱいあるんだけど、
That's right, amazingly, this time in Takane Lui history—there's a lot, but
鷹嶺ルイ史上初のオリジナルアニメMV、フルアニメMVをね、作らせていただきました！
for the first time in Takane Lui history, we had a full original anime MV made for us!
すごかった、めちゃぬるぬる動いてた。ぬるぬる動いてたでしょ？
It was amazing, it moved so smoothly. It moved smoothly, right?
しかも、なんか…私が好きそうな絵のタッチじゃない？おお、確かにね！
And plus, like... isn't that an art style I'd like? Oh, true, yeah!
なんと、私ですね、すごいもう、かねてより、あの、MV作っていただけたとな…はい。あの、思っていた
And amazingly, me... for a long time, I had been hoping to have an MV made by... yes. Um, I was thinking of...
安田現象さんに…あの！？あの安田現象さんに…あの安田現象さんですか！？そうだよ、大丈夫ですか？安田現象さんですか！？そうだね、大丈夫ですか？
...Yasuda Gensho-san! What!? That Yasuda Gensho-san... Is that Yasuda Gensho-san!? That's right, are you okay? Is it Yasuda Gensho-san!? That's right, are you okay?
はい、あの、安田現象さんに作成していただいたフルアニメーションMVとなっております。
Yes, it's a full animation music video created by Gensho Yasuda.
うわあ、すごい！サムネも可愛い。
Wow, amazing! The thumbnail is cute too.
可愛いでしょう？うん。
Isn't it cute? Yeah.
あ、カンペ出してます。
Ah, you're holding cue cards.
あ、カンペ出してるね。
Ah, you are holding cue cards.
ということで、このね、「DARE?」というのは内面にいる、まあ私の、私結構内面にアンチ持ってるんですけど、
So, this song "DARE?" is about having an anti inside ourselves... Well, I actually have an anti inside myself.
あ、そうなの？
Oh, is that so?
自分ルリのアンチを持ってるんですけども、
I have an anti-Rui inside myself,
「お前本当にこれでいいのか？」みたいなね。
thinking things like, "Are you really okay with this?"
お前本当に、いや、やれんのか？みたいな。そ、え、このなんか感情って誰な？みたいな。お、え、私な、私なの？なんで私、私を否定してるの？みたいな。
Like, "Hey really, can you actually do it?" And "Whose emotion is this anyway?" "Oh, wait, it's me? It's me? Why am I denying myself?" like that.
そういうね、深、誰？っていうね。そういう楽曲に仕上がっておりますし、それを
That kind of deep... "Who?" That's the kind of song it's finished as, and...
てか、うわ、誰？
Wait, whoa, who?
誰？
Who?
誰なの？私なの？
Who is it? Is it me?
という、えー、楽曲になっておりますので、これからもちょっとMVもね、あの、プレミア公開させていただきますので、ぜひぜひ楽しんでいただければなと思いますし、結構耳に残るサウンドになってますのでね。
So it's that kind of song, and we'll be premiering the MV too, so I hope you all will enjoy it, and it has a sound that really sticks in your ears.
ね、もう後ろでインスト流れてますけど。
Yeah, the instrumental is already playing in the background.
え、これ早くフル聴きたいし、もうなんだったら今から歌ってもらえませんか？
Hey, I want to hear the full version soon, can you sing it right now?
え？え？え？
Eh? Eh? Eh?
え、一緒に歌いますか？
Eh, shall we sing it together?
えっ、え、うーんと、ちゃ、ちゃ、ちゃ、ちゃ、う、へい、へい、ちょっと歌えなさそうですね。
Uh, um, cha cha cha cha, um, hey, hey, looks like we can't sing it.
ということで、この後、実は「誰」を先行で歌わさせていただきます！
So, actually, we'll be performing "Dare?" ahead of time right after this!
え、そんなの！私は端から見てますということで、
Eh, really! I'll be watching from the sidelines, so...
え、ま、待っててね、あの、ご飯食べ、ご飯食べよ一緒に。
Wait, you know, let's eat, let's eat a meal together.
あ、分かったわかった。じゃ、舞台、それで見ますわ。この後、じゃあご飯ということで、よろしくお願いします。
Ah, okay okay. Then I'll watch from the stage. Afterwards, let's have a meal, looking forward to it.
てか、ふわゆ誰？じゃ。
Wait, "Fuwayu Dare?" huh.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
あ、すいちゃんでした。ありがとうございます、みんな！ありがとうー！
Ah, that was Suichan. Thank you everyone! Thank you!
えー、心強かった助っ人すいちゃんもいなくなり、私一人でですね、えー、新曲「ラピスラズリ」にも入っております曲、「誰」を歌わせていただきます。
Um, with my reliable helper Suichan gone, I will now perform the song "Dare?", which is also included in my new single "Lapis Lazuli", all by myself.
ふう、ちょっと水飲んでいいですか？水飲みますよ。水飲みます。
Phew, can I have some water? I'll drink some water. I'll drink water.
えー、それでは皆さん、聞いてください。……誰？
Um, everyone, please listen. ...Dare?
誰だ 誰
Who is it, who?
どちらさま どちらさま
Which one are you? Which one are you?
果たしてどう ふわゆ How are you?
I wonder, Fuwayu? How are you?
お元気で 一足お先に
Stay well, a step ahead of you.
てかふわゆ？
I mean, Fuwayu?
昨日の自分がだいたい楕円から はみ出さないように
Trying not to protrude from the roughly oval shape of yesterday's self,
ひとまわり小さな円を描くような
drawing a slightly smaller circle around yourself.
ゴールのバウンドが少しずつ ひどくなるさまを
Watching the bounds of the goal get gradually worse,
すべもなく眺めているような気分でしょう
feeling as if you're watching it helplessly.
ところであなた、誰？
By the way, who are you?
誰だ 誰
Who is it, who?
どちらさま どちらさま
Which one are you? Which one are you?
親愛なる果てさて 察知して上げないわ
Dearest at the end, I won't figure it out for you.
ふわゆ
Fuwayu...
ふわゆゆゆゆ どちらさま？
Fuwayuyu... Which one are you?
First to first こんにちは
First to first, hello.
幽霊もなってだって アウトサイダー for 自分 自分
Even becoming ghosts, outsider for myself, myself.
ぬけがらい たからくらい だからくらい 遠巻きに手構え 手構え 手構えわ
Shell left behind, treasure-like, so-like, holding back from afar, holding back, holding back...
誰？昨日の自分は
Who? Yesterday's self
自分の手で組み立てましょう
let's build it with our own hands.
てかふわゆ？
I mean, Fuwayu?
誰？ ぬけがらい ぬけがらい からからから
Who? Shell left behind, shell left behind, dryly.
人の目は私川、私川、私のこと見張り続けてる
People's eyes are watching me, watching over me, watching me all the time,
なのできっと背筋伸ばし 方向を越えるの
so I'm sure I'll straighten my back and surpass the direction.
花は誰に見られずとも美しく咲くと言うけど
They say flowers bloom beautifully even if seen by no one,
孵化や虫にもそっぽ抜かれたら 咲き方を改めだろ
but if even caterpillars ignore you, you'd better change how you bloom.
誰だ 誰
Who is it, who?
どちらさま どちらさま
Which one are you? Which one are you?
親愛なる果てさて 察知して上げないわ
Dearest at the end, I won't figure it out for you.
誰？
Who?
ふわゆゆゆゆ どちらさま？ First to first こんばんは
Fuwayuyu... Which one are you? First to first, good evening.
幽霊もなってだって アウトサイダー for 自分 自分
Even becoming ghosts, outsider for myself, myself.
ぬけがらい たからくらい だからくらい 遠巻きに手構え 手構え 手構え
Shell left behind, treasure-like, so-like, holding back from afar, holding back, holding back...
誰だ 誰！？ そちら様 どちら様！？
Who is it?! Which one are you?
はてさてと フーアーユー？
Who could it be? Who are you?
ハウアーユー？ お元気で
How are you? Doing well,
一足お先に てか フーアーユー？
taking a step ahead. Wait, who are you?
ハバユー？ 誰？
How about you? Who?
look alike, and
look alike, alike, alike me
どなた様？ どちら様？
Which of you? Which one?
反転させろ これは誰だ？
Flip it around, who is this?
誰であれ 見せつけるだけ
Whoever it is, just showing off
Take a look, my dear.
Have a nice stare.
はい、ということで今日のライブは
Yes, so today's live
これにて終了となります。皆さん本当にありがとうございました！
will conclude with this. Thank you all so very much!
改めて告知をさせていただきます。
I'd like to make an announcement once again.
セカンドアルバム「Lapis Lazuli」が12月3日に発売されます！
My 2nd album, "Lapis Lazuli," will be released on December 3rd!
え、予約は、え、もうできますので、
Um, reservations can, um, already be made, so
え、こちらから、こちらからぜひぜひご予約をしてください。
um, please, please make your reservations right here.
もうすごく頑張った、え、楽曲、
Since it's filled with songs I worked extremely hard on,
頑張って頑張って歌った楽曲ばかりになりますので、ぜひぜひ早く皆さんに聴いていただきたいなと思いますので、
songs I sang with all my heart, I really want everyone to hear them as soon as possible, so
え、ぜひセカンドアルバムもよろしくお願いします！
um, please look forward to my second album as well!
え、そして、え、豪華なスライドボックスパッケージでイラストブックや缶バッチ、
And, um, we have a completely produced limited edition featuring a gorgeous slipcase package,
直筆サイン入りのジャケットカードなどがついてくる完全生産限定盤！
complete with an art book, a pin badge, a signed jacket card, and more!
え、そしてランダムアナザージャケット全5種から1枚、数量限定ランダムで
And, um, the regular edition features one of five random alternate jackets,
直筆サインとメッセージがつく通常版、各種法人特典ももりだくさんでございます！
with a random limited quantity including a hand-signed autograph and message, plus plenty of retailer-specific bonuses!
え、秋葉原ゲーマーズ本店さんにてリリース記念のミニライブもやる予定でございます。
Um, we also plan to hold a release mini-live at the Akihabara Gamers main store.
そして、先ほど歌いました「DARE!?」本日24時にデジタルリリースされますし、
And, "DARE!?"—which I sang earlier—will be digitally released tonight at midnight,
このあとすぐフルアニメーションもMV公開されます！
and the full animated MV will premiere right after this!
え、このままで見ていただければ、え、自動で、たしか、たしか自動で
Um, if you just keep watching, um, it will automatically—I believe, automatically
MVに飛びますのでぜひぜひフルアニメーション、あの、私自身初のフルアニメーションになっておりますので、ぜひ可愛く仕上がったので見ていただけると嬉しいでございます。
jump to the MV, so please check out the full animation! Since this is my very first full animation, I'd be so happy if you watched it, as it turned out super cute.
はい、え、今回、あの重大告知ライブということで、皆さんね、
Yes, um, since this was a major announcement live today, you guys probably,
あの、ソロライブなんじゃないかってすごい、あの、予想してくださっていたんですけれども、私はですね、まだあのソロライブは、あの、決まっておりません！
um, were all guessing, "Could it be a solo live?!" But you see, I haven't actually decided on a solo live yet!
ですがですね、私、あの、音楽をやりたいと、え、心に決めてからですね、え、夢であるファーストアルバムがリリースできたり、そしてファーストアルバムをみなさんが買ってくださったから、
However, ever since I resolved in my heart that I wanted to make music, um, my dream of releasing a first album came true, and because you all bought my first album,
え、こうやってセカンドアルバムを全国流通として、え、発売することができました！
um, I was able to release my second album nationwide like this!
え、1千万再生のMVを、え、が2つも、え、できましたし、そのほかの楽曲もたくさんたくさんみんなに愛してもらって、え、再生数もすごい伸びて、
Um, I got two MVs with over 10 million views, and so many of you have loved all my other songs, so the view counts have grown tremendously.
もうみんなのおかげでですね、私、あの、こんなに、あの、音楽をやっていてよかったなと、
Thanks to all of you, I've really felt, "I'm so glad I've been doing music like this,"
今でも、え、そしてこれからもきっとと思うと、
and thinking that even now and into the future...
え、ソロライブ次はですね、え、夢を一つずつ叶えてきたからこそ、次はもうソロライブしかないやろ！
As for a solo live next... since I've made my dreams come true one by one, next up surely has to be a solo live!
なので、え、必ず、え、皆さんと一緒にソロライブを、え、夢見て、みんなと一緒にもうここから走り出したいなと思います。
So, um, I definitely want to dream of a solo live together with everyone, and start running forward from here together with you all.
え、ぜひぜひ皆さん、え、ファーストに引き続きセカンドアルバムも、え、お手元に取っていただけると嬉しいです。
So I'd be so happy if you all could get your hands on my second album as well, following the first.
なので、え、これからまた鷹嶺ルイと一緒にソロライブをめざしましょう！目指してくれますか？
So, let's aim for a solo live together with Takane Lui again from here on! Will you aim for it with me?
ん？ ん？ 目指してくれるか？
Hm? Hm? Will you aim for it?
もちろん、え、ありがとう！
Of course, um, thank you!
はい、もう本当にみんなの、え、力がないと、私は、え、きっとソロライブに、え、到達できないと思うので、
Yes, I truly believe that without everyone's support and strength, I wouldn't be able to reach a solo live.
私も頑張りますが、みんなも一緒に走り続けていただけると嬉しいです。え、ルイ友のみんな、そして、ルイのことは、まあ2番手3番手ぐらいに推してるよというみんな、
I'll do my best too, but I'd be so happy if you kept running along with me. Um, all my Luimates, and everyone who supports me as maybe your second or third favorite,
そして、ホロリスのみんな、そしてこれからまた出会うであろう、え、鷹嶺ルイを知っていただく皆さん、皆さんの協力が必要です。
and all the Holofans, and everyone who will get to know Takane Lui from now on—I need everyone's cooperation.
ぜひこれからも鷹嶺ルイをよろしくお願いします！
Please continue supporting Takane Lui!
はい、ということで
So, with that said,
じゃあ次のね、
well, for the next one,
ま、次重大告知があるときにはもう超重大告知としてね、
When the next major announcement comes,
その内容が発表できるようにこれからも頑張ります。
I'll do my best so we can share the details.
みんな本当に今日はありがとうございます！
Everyone, thank you so much for today!
セカンドアルバムも楽しみにしててね
Look forward to the second album too,
これからもどんどん情報が出てくると思いますので
and since more info will be coming out soon,
お楽しみに！
please look forward to it!
またねー！
See you later!